weddingdirectory.com 2012-01-24

# WeddingDirectory Privacy Policy

This document was last updated on March 31, 2010.

**1\. Acknowledgment and acceptance of terms**

WeddingDirectory is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement sets forth our current privacy practices with regard to the information we collect when you or your computer interact with our website.   By accessing WeddingDirectory.com, you acknowledge and fully understand WeddingDirectory’s Privacy Statement and freely consent to the information collection and use practices described in this Website Privacy Statement.

**2\. Participating Merchant Policies**

Related services and offerings with links from this website, including vendor sites, have their own privacy statements that can be viewed by clicking on the corresponding links within each respective website. Online merchants and others who participate in WeddingDirectory’s services are encouraged to participate in industry privacy initiatives and to take a responsible attitude towards consumer privacy.  However, since we do not have direct control over the policies or practices of participating merchants and other third parties, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or contents of those sites.  We recommend and encourage that you always review the privacy policies of merchants and other third parties before you provide any personal information or complete any transaction with such parties.

**3\. Information We Collect and How We Use It**

WeddingDirectory collects certain information from and about its users three ways: directly from our Web Server logs, the user, and with Cookies.

**a.** **Web Server Logs**.

When you visit our Website, we may track information to administer the site and analyze its usage.  Examples of information we may track include:

     -  Your Internet protocol address.

     -  The kind of browser or computer you use.

     -  Number of links you click within the site.

     -  State or country from which you accessed the site.

     -  Date and time of your visit.

     -  Name of your Internet service provider.

     -  Web page you linked to our site from.

     -  Pages you viewed on the site.

**b. Use of Cookies**

WeddingDirectory may use cookies to personalize or enhance your user experience.  A cookie is a small text file that is placed on your hard disk by a Web page server.  Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.  Cookies are uniquely assigned to you, and can only be read by a Web Server in the domain that issued the cookie to you. 

One of the primary purposes of cookies is to provide a convenience feature to save you time.  For example, if you personalize a web page, or navigate within a site, a cookie helps the site to recall your specific information on subsequent visits.  Hence, this simplifies the process of delivering relevant content and eases site navigation by providing and saving your preferences and login information as well as providing personalized functionality. 

WeddingDirectory reserves the right to share aggregated site statistics with partner companies, but does not allow other companies to place cookies on our website unless there is a temporary, overriding customer value (such as merging into WeddingDirectory.com a site that relies on third-party cookies).

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies.  Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you reject cookies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may disable some of the functionality on our Website.

**4\. Use of Web Beacons or GIF files**

WeddingDirectory web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons – sometimes also called single-pixel gifs – that allow WeddingDirectory to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services.  WeddingDirectory may include Web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

Some of these Web beacons may be placed by third party service providers to help determine the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns or email communications.  These Web beacons may be used by these service providers to place a persistent cookie on your computer.  This allows the service provider to recognize your computer each time you visit certain pages or emails and compile anonymous information in relation to those page views, which in turn enables us and our service providers to learn which advertisements and emails bring you to our website and how you use the site.  WeddingDirectory prohibits web beacons from being used to collect or access your personal information.

**5\. You can choose to   "opt-out" at any time.**

Upon enrollment, Wedding Directory members are opted-in to receive transactional information, newsletters and special email promotions. Some information is exclusive to our emails and are not even shown on our site. On every one of these emails you are given the choice to unsubscribe from the mailing. You may also login to your account and change your email preferences. For your security, you will be prompted to login before updating any account information.

Please allow up to 7 business days to be completely opted-out from Wedding Directory broadcasts. You may receive several additional emails from us while we are processing your unsubscribe request.

**6\. Changes to this Statement**

WeddingDirectory has the discretion to occasionally update this privacy statement.  When we do, we will also revise the “updated” date at the top of this Privacy page.  We encourage you to periodically review this privacy statement to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect.  Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this privacy statement and any updates.

**7\. Contacting Us**

If you have questions regarding our Privacy Statement, its implementation, failure to adhere to this Privacy Statement and/or our general practices, please contact us at [privacy@weddingdirectory.com](mailto:privacy@weddingdirectory.com)

WeddingDirectory will use commercially reasonable efforts to promptly respond and resolve any problem or question.
